<?xml version="1.0"?><metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><title>Metropolitan Planning Organization (MPO) Area</title><origin>Metropolitan Transportation Services - Metropolitan Council</origin><pubinfo><publish>Metropolitan Council</publish></pubinfo><pubdate>20170215</pubdate></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>This the Metropolitan Planning Organization (MPO) area for the Twin Cities. The shape covers the 7 county area as well as the urbanized area that extends beyond the 7 county area.

Under state law, the Met Council's jurisdiction covers the 7 county area - Anoka, Carver, Dakota, Hennepin, Ramsey, Scott, and Washington counties.

Under federal rules, the MPO must plan for the entire urbanized area, which is a Census defined area. After the 2010  Census, the urbanized area for the Twin Cities extended beyond the 7 county area into Wright and Sherburne counties.

Thus, for the first time, the MPO jurisdiction area for the Met Council needed to extend beyond the 7 counties. 

Working with MnDOT, the census defined urbanized area was smoothed and this data file was the officially accepted MPO area for the Twin Cities. 
</abstract><purpose>To delineate the extent of the Metropolitan Planning Organization Area </purpose><supplinf>Twin Cities 7 County Area (Anoka, Carver, Dakota, Hennepin, Ramsey, Scott and Washington) and the urbanized portions of urbanized portions of Wright and Sherburne Counties</supplinf></descript><timeperd><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>20170215</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>As needed</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-94.012</westbc><eastbc>-92.732</eastbc><northbc>45.415</northbc><southbc>44.471</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><place><placekey>Twin Cities, Anoka County, Carver County, Dakota County, Hennepin County, Ramsey County, Scott County, Washington County</placekey></place><theme><themekey>MPO, planning, urbanized area, UZA, TMA, census </themekey><themekt>None</themekt></theme></keywords><accconst>None</accconst><useconst>None</useconst><native>ArcView 9x</native><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Metropolitan Council</cntorg><cntper>Dave Vessel</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Senior Planner-ASF</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>390 Robert Street North</address><city>St. Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55101-1805</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651.602.1646</cntvoice><cntemail>david.vessel@metc.state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></ptcontac></idinfo><dataqual><attracc><attraccr>This is regional planning level data and is not intended to be used for anything but regional planning.  Some alignments may have been shifted for cartographic display purposes.</attraccr></attracc><logic>The dataset is topologically 'clean'.</logic><complete>Entire seven county geographic area and portains of Wright and Sherburne counties </complete><lineage><procstep><procdesc>This data area combination of US Census urbanized area files and county boundaries. Small changes were approved by MnDOT and the Met Council. </procdesc></procstep><srcinfo><srcscale></srcscale></srcinfo></lineage></dataqual><spdoinfo><indspref>None</indspref><direct>Vector</direct><mgmg3obj>line shapes</mgmg3obj><mgmg3til>One layer for entire seven county region.</mgmg3til></spdoinfo><distinfo><distliab>NOTICE:  The Geographic Information System (GIS) Data to which this notice is attached are made available pursuant to the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13).  THE GIS DATA ARE PROVIDED TO YOU AS IS AND WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY AS TO THEIR PERFORMANCE, MERCHANTABILITY, OR FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  The GIS Data were developed by the Metropolitan Council for its own internal business purposes.  The Metropolitan Council does not represent or warrant that the GIS Data or the data documentation are error-free, complete, current, or accurate.  You are responsible for any consequences resulting from your use of the GIS Data or your reliance on the GIS Data.  You should consult the data documentation for this particular GIS Data to determine the limitations of the GIS Data and the precision with which the GIS Data may depict distance, direction, location, or other geographic features.  If you transmit or provide the GIS Data (or any portion of it) to another user, it is recommended that the GIS Data include a copy of this disclaimer and this metadata.</distliab><stdorder><digform><digtinfo><formname>ArcView Shape file</formname><formvern>ArcView: 9x</formvern><transize>0.1 MB for Zip file.</transize></digtinfo></digform><ordering>See Online Linkage Below</ordering></stdorder><distrib><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Metropolitan Council</cntorg><cntper>Jon Hoekenga</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>GIS System Administrator</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>390 Robert Street North</address><city>St. Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55101-1805</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651.602.1561</cntvoice><cntemail>jonathan.hoekenga@metc.state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></distrib></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20170215</metd><metstdn>Minnesota Geographic Metadata Guidelines</metstdn><metstdv>1.2</metstdv><metextns><onlink>http://www.gis.state.mn.us/stds/metadata.htm</onlink></metextns><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Metropolitan Council</cntorg><cntper>Dave Vessel</cntper></cntperp><cntpos>Senior Planner-ASF</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>390 Robert Street North</address><city>St. Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55101-1805</postal></cntaddr><cntvoice>651.602.1646</cntvoice><cntemail>david.vessel@metc.state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></metc></metainfo><Esri><ModDate>20110721</ModDate><ModTime>16044100</ModTime><CreaDate>20130717</CreaDate><CreaTime>14085700</CreaTime><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><DataProperties><itemProps><itemLocation><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\rafs2a.mc.local\Wikenrl\2030 transit\data\Transitways2030</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></itemLocation></itemProps><copyHistory><copy source="L:\Metadata\Layers\Transitways2030" dest="\\rafs2a.mc.local\Wikenrl\2030 transit\data\Transitways2030" date="20130717" time="14085700"></copy></copyHistory></DataProperties></Esri><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20110721</mdDateSt><spref><horizsys><planar><gridsys><gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn><utm><utmzone>15</utmzone></utm></gridsys><planci><plandu>meters</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>NAD83</horizdn><ellips>GRS80</ellips></geodetic></horizsys></spref></metadata>